<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scribblefilter on Hamsters Byte</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/scribblefilter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scribblefilter on Hamsters Byte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/scribblefilter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribble Filter Now Available and Other Muses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/11/08/scribble_filter_now_available_and_other_muses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/11/08/scribble_filter_now_available_and_other_muses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got the sale software all installed so I can sell the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spreadsheetbudget.com/products/scribble-filter/&#34;&gt;Scribble
Filter&lt;/a&gt;.
There’s still a few changes I wanted to make with it. I wasn’t entirely
thinking when I added the ability to filter ranges directly when I add
(among others). I should have made it &lt;a href=&#34;http://office.microsoft.com/en-us/excel-help/using-structured-references-with-excel-tables-HA010155686.aspx#BMstructured_reference_syntax_rules&#34;&gt;more compliant to what Microsoft
does&lt;/a&gt;.
I’ll be working on changing that around now. It will probably be a
little while before I incorporate all of that into the filter. If the
sales do well then I’ll make it more powerful otherwise I won’t be able
to justify the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note. It is interesting how long this project took. I spent
over 225 hours working on it. Of course, if I were to do it again I
could probably slice that time down. So, that will take quite a bit of
money to make this project worth it! For a programmer marketing can be
the most difficult part and it is also the most important part. You can
make the best program in the world, but if you can’t market it, it might
as well not even exist!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try and get the trial version out in the next week or so. Wife is
about to have a baby so it might take a little longer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>